Finding Aid for the Judith Saunders papers, circa 1970s-2000s LSC.2221
UCLA Library Special Collections
Judith Saunders papers
circa 1970s-2000s
LSC.2221
UCLA Library Special Collections
0.8 linear feet (2 boxes)
Judith Saunders was a registered nurse and advocate for gay and lesbian rights. This collection contains materials that document Judith Saunder's research and work as a registered nurse, as well as her involvement in LGBT organizations. Included are newsletters, organizational documents, meeting minutes, survey materials, reports, fliers, ephemera and fundraising material, primarily from the June Mazer Lesbian Archive and Southern California Women for Understanding. Also included are research materials compiled by Saunders, as well as articles and research conducted by Saunders, primarily concerned with HIV/AIDS and lesbian health.
Saunders, Judith, 1939-
Conditions Governing Access
COLLECTION STORED OFF-SITE AT SRLF: Open for research. All requests to access special collections material must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Acquisition Information
Gift, Judith Saunders, 2013. This collection is part of an outreach and collection-building partnership between the June L. Mazer Lesbian Archives, the UCLA Center for the Study of Women (CSW) and the UCLA Library.
Biography
Judith Saunders (1939-) was a registered nurse and advocate for gay and lesbian rights. Saunders received her bachelor’s degree from the University of Cincinnati, her master’s from Boston University, and her doctorate from UCSF. Saunders was an assistant professor of nursing at USC, as well as an assistant research scientist at the City of Hope Medical Center in Duarte, CA.
Throughout her career she published works on topics relating to the affective relationship between nurses and their patients, specific needs and risks of working with gay and lesbian populations, people who are HIV positive and their families and heterosexism in the medical profession. She was the associate editor of the 2002 publication Before Stonewall: Activists for Gay and Lesbian Rights in Historical Context.
Scope and Content
This collection contains materials that document Judith Saunder's research and work as a registered nurse, as well as her involvement in LGBT organizations. Included are newsletters, organizational documents, meeting minutes, survey materials, reports, fliers, ephemera and fundraising material, primarily from the June Mazer Lesbian Archive and Southern California Women for Understanding (SCWU). SCWU was an educational non-profit organization, formed in 1976 and dedicated to “enhancing the quality of life for [the lesbian] community and for lesbians nationwide, creative and positive exchange about homosexuality, [and] changing stereotypical images of lesbians.”
Also included are research materials compiled by Saunders, as well as articles and research conducted by Saunders, primarily concerned with HIV/AIDS and lesbian health.
Organization and Arrangement
Materials in this collection are organized alphabetically by folder title.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
COLLECTION CONTAINS DIGITAL MATERIALS: Special equipment or further processing may be required for viewing. All requests to access special collections material must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
June L. Mazer Lesbian Archive at UCLA.; June L. Mazer Lesbian Archives.; Saunders, Judith, 1939- -- Archives.; Southern California Women for Understanding.
- Articles and Research Conducted by Judith Saunders, 1979-1999 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Clippings, circa 1980s-1990s (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, circa 1980s (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Fliers and Brochures, circa 1980s-1990s (Box 1, Folder 4)
- June L. Mazer Lesbian Archive: Organizational Documents, 1985-1998 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- June L. Mazer Lesbian Archive: June Mazer Materials, 1987-1989 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- June L. Mazer Lesbian Archive: Bunny McCulloch Materials, 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- June L. Mazer Lesbian Archive: Ephemera, circa 1990s-2000's (Box 1, Folder 8)
- June L. Mazer Lesbian Archive: Fundraising and Financial Material, circa 1990s (Box 1, Folder 9)
- June L. Mazer Lesbian Archive: Newsletters, 1991-2001 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Newsletters, 1982-1989 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  Scope and Content
  Includes newsletters from Southern California Women for Understanding, Matrices and Connexxus.
- Photograph, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  Scope and Contents note
  Photograph of Dr. Evelyn Hooker and unidentified man on Hooker's trip to China (People-to-People Mental Health Delegation).
- Research Publications, circa 1970s-1991 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Southern California Women for Understanding Survey, 1985-1990 (Box 2, Folders 4-7)
  These folders contain six 5.25 inch floppy disks.
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
  COLLECTION CONTAINS DIGITAL MATERIALS: Special equipment or further processing may be required for viewing. All requests to access special collections material must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.